[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody
welcome back to the asket show after a
brief Hiatus of just a week I hope you
are all doing fantastic very good it's
great to see your smiling faces once
again virtually so let us see whose
smiling faces are there with us today
let me see all is there I can see Satish
parat Chan V1 VH special operator Kiran
lanii Kunal
nagaro adya Mishra hyper NS pronam red
Anique xus Yus zus random skull hello DH
Kumar Putra Roshan J geopolitical dub sh
vsam pray Paul goo harmit Singh Nihari
kupta virj deshmuk pan Kumar Singh Krish
s r Ripper Robinson NAD Sak sakan jadav
viand Panda Dr Dr suryakant dager havit
chavda Krishna Singh ragir Sal
geopolitical du again hello winter
Rangers wolf rudra hi uh
b g abishek arush somi Jan shashwat
mukarji
rishikesh Das Gupta sarak saat Aditya
Tomi muhammadan shik abishek arush
Mahajan ARA Indra Mano
Kakashi barti edits Hakuna johnv why
Krish and everybody else okay today I'm
going to take questions from the live
chat all interactive all live so go
ahead fire away your questions there's a
lot happening in the world as always and
we're going to address as much of that
as is possible in this session and I'm
going to have another s session tomorrow
as well in which I will take questions
that you have asked in the comments so
with that said let us see who all is
asking me
questions what questions do we have mlin
has questions
um okay let's take mclovin's question
allegedly Indian army weapons were used
by Cookie terrorists in the recent
bombing Terror attacks in Manipur how
did this happen yeah allegedly this is
what one hears one hears that some of
these terrorists wear allegedly uniforms
that seem to have Indian marking Indian
army insignia what does it mean we have
no idea maybe these are stolen from
somewhere maybe okay we we have no idea
there's 100 ways in which something this
could happen maybe they are they are
fake uniforms uh weapons also you know
circulate weapons also tend to circulate
around uh let's say in the hypothetical
situation you find AK-47s with
terrorists does it mean that Russia is
involved in the matter because the AK-47
is a Russian weapon it doesn't mean that
Russia is involved similarly if Indian
army weapons are discovered in the hands
of terrorists it doesn't necessarily
mean anything at all it could mean a
thousand different things so the point
is that we don't know
what uh how whether these allegations
first of all are true or not and
secondly if they are true then how did
this happen there's a thousand ways in
which it could happen
so uh the best course of action right
now is to not engage in
speculations okay uh we have our hands
full when it comes to Manipur it's a big
problem as we know it's crossborder
terrorism by Foreign actors the cookie
terrorists who have been infiltrating in
very large numbers in the past few years
because of the open border policy that
we've had since the since 1947 1949
whatever you want to say uh so it's not
a problem that this government has
created but they're going to have to
deal with it and I assure you
something's going to
happen the solution to the Manipur issue
to the cookie terrorism issue doesn't
lie in Manipur it doesn't lie on Indian
Territory let me just keep it at
that
okay okay um Brides SK says who won in a
recent presidential debate between
Kamala Harris and Donald
Trump
um well if you look at the American
Media the mainstream media they're
portraying it as as kind of a win for
Kamala Harris okay but as we know the
American Media the mainstream media is
essentially an arm of the is the Press
arm of the democratic party if you look
at uh the clippings that are circulating
on social media you can see that Donald
Trump has kind of hit hard at Kamala
Harris and Kamala Harris
essentially she maintained a smug uh and
Superior expression all the time hotty
expression all the time that doesn't
mean she won the
debate and she it's clear that she
rehearsed a lot for the debate lots of
90 intervention she had rehearsed over
and over again she was able to do that
but that doesn't necessarily mean that
she won the debate it looks like she has
done better than what most people
expected no I would say that it's more
like a draw and a trump is going to have
to do better probably the next time
around uh you cannot uh take anybody uh
lightly even if it is what's her name
Kamala Harris so I think it's kind of a
draw from my
perspective and
yeah yeah that's
what shaswat mukari asks is Winston
Churchill a hero was he a hero or a
villain there's a lot of uh
introspection happening right now in the
west when it comes to wiinston Churchill
there's a lot of reevaluation of World
War I World War II happening right now
in the west not just in India we have
been saying for a long time Churchill
was a monster he Unleashed a genocide on
the people of Eastern India mainly
Bengal an artificially engineered famine
the last of the artificial engineered
artificially engineered famines that the
British Unleashed upon India the last of
the famines and Churchill oversaw uh the
engineering and execution of that
famine clearly a monster he killed
probably more people than Adolf Hitler
did Churchill okay in India so we are
very clear about this we as in you we
all I mean shat mukarji you Bengali
aren't you are you not aware of what he
did right where I mean in in
Bengal I mean how can you even ask the
question obviously was a
monster he genocided at least mean
between four to eight million of our
people right in eastern India in Bengal
the Bengal genocide the Bengal famine
they call it and the Western historians
may have made all kinds of excuses
pathetic lame excuses to to kind of
explain that to to try and claim that
Churchill did not mean to kill anybody
and and so on so forth you know all
kinds of ridiculous pathetic lame
excuses the fact is it doesn't matter
what he meant what he didn't mean what
his intentions where what the only thing
that matters is what were the results of
his actions that's it and that was
genocide artificially engineered famine
the food grains everything was there and
it was deliberated deliberately shipped
off to Greece or wherever else and the
people of India were left to staff the
people of Bengal
absolute monster and there's a whole lot
more what it did I mean he was not I
mean even if you disregard this
particular thing that he did okay U his
actions in Africa also are tent amount
to Massacre and genocide okay in case
you're not aware you should read about
his life's history his career in
Africa um southern Africa to be more
specific then um his actions during
World War
I he was the architect of uh the galipo
disaster the galipo
disaster uh the it was against Turkey
right the agency the the they wanted to
take Constantinople by sending a large
Naval Force there and they were taken
out by one guy Mustafa kimal Ataturk the
guy who turned the tide Churchill was
made to look like a fool and
unfortunately lots of Indian fire
soldiers died in in that campaign
fighting on behalf of the British
Churchill was not just a monster and a
villain he was kind of a loser as well
okay so yeah there we have
it geopolitical du says is Russia
mediator between bat and China PR Paul
says what's going on with China is there
really some kind of temporary
understanding for mutual
benefits I think it's too it's too early
to say what's going on between Barat and
China whether you look at prai's
question or geopolitical Dub's question
is Russia mediating between India and
China Barat and China look right now the
deal is
this China has been essentially
encircled by the Americans uh
geographically uh let's go to the map
and we'll see what I mean by that so
where's the map here is map yes so we
have China here uh east of China you
have Japan South Korea then you have the
island chains all the way to Guam you
know this island of Guam here all
controlled by the US Philippines is
controlled by the us whether you realize
or not these countries are essentially
controlled by the US Japan and South
Korea are under immense US military
occupation permanent occupation when it
comes to papini Indonesia Malaysia
Vietnam southeast Asia all of these are
essentially to some uh to some degree or
the other controlled uh by the US the
Chinese have made a big big enemy of
India because of their actions over the
past 70 years so China doesn't have a
friend there Pakistan is once again us
vasal when it comes to Afghanistan you
could say it's kind of on the US side
and then you have the S ex Soviet
republics which are more uh under the
Russian sphere of influence and the
Chinese sphere of influence then you
have Mongolia which is a buffer State
between between Russia and China and
that's what you have China is to a large
extent encircled uh there's a trade war
going on between the US and China and
the Americans can deal with China and
and deal with the Chinese economically
as well and militarily China is no match
for the US okay whether you believe
realize it or not so China is under
Strife Bangladesh they were trying to
vuo Bangladesh Bangladesh is gone it's
now a newly mined US vasal state and
then you have Burma which is which is
torn in a tremendous Civil War right now
which is kind of a proxy war between the
United States and its its puppet forces
and various other factions which
essentially are the Earth or or whatever
exists or remains of the burmes
government which historically has been
pro-china so that's the deal so China
cannot and China is really really
feeling the heat right now and so is
India so is India we have two newly
minted vasal States on both sides on
East and West Pakistan and East Pakistan
okay both are wasal states of the US the
Americans are trying to carve out an
independent artificial Christian Nation
from the Far East of India at parts of
Burma which is Cookie Land and they have
Unleashed proxy terrorism in Manipur and
other in the Northeast the Far East of
India so India is facing a tremendous
amount of heat from the Americans China
is facing a tremendous amount of heat
from the Americans the Americans are
engaging in subnational diplomacy to
destabilize India and so much more um
industrial scale Christian conversions
in various parts of India all kinds of
destabilizing activities the Americans
uh are making it very clear to India
that we not your friends they're making
it very clear to India the Chinese have
known this for a very long time the
Russians are essentially engaged in a
proxy war against NATO which which they
had no choice but to start uh so India
Russia China uh are on the receiving end
of the uh of the us Empire's
actions so does it make sense for India
and China to come together I mean if
India and China have to come together
the owners is on China to prove that
they are trustworthy because all the bad
blood that exists between India and
China is entirely because of China India
has not been the aggressor or the
provocator in any of these cases China
claims Indian Territory indan India
doesn't claim Chinese territory China in
the in the in the 20th century used to
uh support uh anti-india uh insurgents
and separatists in various parts of
India and so much more there's a whole
lot of actions of Chinese have done so
if things are to be normalized the onus
is on China let me repeat this if the
Chinese want things to get better
between India and China because it makes
sense H then the owners is on you my
friends you've got to prove to India
that you can be trusted and we're going
to take it one small step at a time and
let's see
may maybe we can do a pilot project
somewhere in the neighborhood yes our
Chinese friends maybe we can do a pilot
project somewhere in our mutual
neighborhood and see if we can we can
work together to a certain
extent and uh to see whether we are
reliable Partners in a small project not
a very small project but not a very
large project either somewhere in our
mutual neighborhood that's what in bat
and China should do is Russia mediating
we don't know I mean if they are
mediating they will it's not going to be
publicized whatever real diplomacy
happens always happens behind closed
doors but let me tell you this it makes
eminent sense for r i to happen Russia
India China and the only obstacle when
it comes to r i is China's Behavior so
the onus is on China but it makes sense
for the three nations to kind of come
together China shouldn't feel threatened
by India India has never been a threat
to China China has been a threat to all
its neighbors China needs to mend its
ways China needs to take several steps
many extra miles walk many extra miles
to demonstrate to Nations like India
that we can take it seriously and kind
of trust it because in the past they
have been tremendously
duplicitous
right Krish sh says is Intergalactic
travel possible Intergalactic travel
possible he here is it possible
well I think we should learn to walk
before we learn to jog and we should
learn to jog before we learn learn to
Sprint we should learn to Sprint before
we learn to fly or whatever so uh from
our perspective we currently have the
technology to send
spacecraft uh to various parts of the
solar system uh when it comes to the
Americans they have sent spacecraft to
various parts of the solar system
including the furthermost minor planet
Pluto uh and two of the probes voyag or
probes are currently on the outskirts of
the solar system you could say that they
are kind of outside the solar system
at least one of those the Pioneer probes
also are quite far and various us us
spacecraft have visited various planets
of the solar system the Americans have
landed humans on the moon we currently
have the U the the International Space
Station which is mainly an American
thing where you have a couple of
astronauts who are stuck there which is
rather unfortunate and silly but okay
that's where we are uh when it comes to
Nations like Japan Japan has achieved a
soft Landing of robotic spacecraft on an
asteroid which is fantastic great
achievement when it comes to Russia they
have done a lot of good work in the past
but recently it looks like they have
kind of regressed a little bit they
recently tried to land a spacecraft on
the moon a couple of days before the
chandran 3 spacecraft and unfortunately
that spacecraft crashed it just made a
hard landing on the moon the
Japanese recently U I think landed a
spacecraft on the moon soft Landing if
I'm not mistaken I hope it was not a
hard Landing not a crash and so on so
there are and we have obviously bhat
India we have achieved soft landing on
the moon chundra 3 on the second attempt
Chan 2 uh had a hard Landing chandrian 3
successfully landed and even did a hop
test and it also sent back the Orbiter
back to Earth orbit so it it it it overd
delivered it it went beyond what was
expected Chan 3 and Barat also obviously
has is the only nation to successfully
send a space craft uh into moon orbit
into M Orbit on the first attempt itself
so there are numerous Nations that have
these capabilities and right now the
most powerful spa space force or most
powerful force in space exploration is
Space
X and they have the technology to send
humans to Mars they currently have it uh
but they will uh implement it or they
will uh Ru it out in a phased manner
they will deploy it in a phased manner
so Elon Musk has recently tweeted that
uh in the next few years humans will
reach Mars on on his largest uh
rocket so right now what's
possible is reaching the reaching Mars
and moon and the moon these two things
are possible for human beings that's the
limit of her possibility of of her
capabilities uh we don't have currently
have the capability to go beyond Mars so
and when it comes to traveling
below uh traveling beyond the solar
system that's Interstellar travel you
see traveling from one star to another
so right now if you use chemical Rockets
the kind of the most powerful Rockets we
have are chemical Rockets they rely on
chemical propulsion the impulse comes
from chemical reactions essentially
exothermic reactions uh so if you rely
on chemical Rockets Interstellar travel
will take tens or hundreds of thousands
of years just reaching the nearest star
if you
use a technology like uh light sales
which is something we we are almost
there almost there maybe a decade or two
so if you use light sales we may be able
to reach the nearest Stellar system
Proxima centor star system in about 30
40 years which is a tremendous like
Quantum Leap essentially so Interstellar
travel could be possible 30 40 years we
may even if we get lucky be able to send
humans on a oneway or even two-way
journey to Proxima centor we don't know
what's out there but we could find out
or we could send robotic
probes so we could be on the U verge of
being able to achieve Interstellar
travel travel between Stars so we
talking about distances of our of a
handful of Li years okay but when it
comes to Intergalactic travel we we
talking about millions of Li years uh
right now we can't even dream of that
right now that is it's feasible uh
according to the rules of physics but
but if you look at our capabilities it's
science it's not Science Fiction it's
almost fantasy okay so Intergalactic
travel let's not think about it right
now let's think about travel within the
solar system we can think about the moon
we can think about Mars we can think
about Venus we can think about traveling
to an asteroid nearby
you know local locally available
asteroid let's say and so on and if you
want to send robotic probes you can
actually begin to think about
breakthrough star short which is a
sending a probe to Proxima centor the
nearest star system Intergalactic travel
way way way in the future not anything
we can do right
now okay not tun Singh says Ajit doal in
Russia visit why we as country need to
explain things to Russia what we did in
Ukraine do you think the purpose of Mr
Ajit D's visit was to go and explain to
President Putin why we why Mr Modi
visited Ukraine and what we were doing
in Ukraine do you think that's why Mr D
has gone to
Moscow yeah we know what came out the
video clipping that came out that was a
video clipping so Mr doal sits across
the table with Mr Putin face to face
it's not that long table it's a friendly
short table okay and he's Mr D is
speaking in h in English and Mr Putin
has this translation thing and he's
nodding and Mr D is saying that Prime
Minister Modi has sent me specially over
here to convey to you directly and
personally uh what happened in Ukraine
and the visit with meeting with Mr
zalinsky and so on so forth that's what
he said in a 30 second or 60c clip to Mr
Putin on camera do you know that diplom
y actually happens behind closed doors
where there are no cameras and do you
think that that was the real purpose of
Mr D's visit to Moscow and his meeting
with Mr Putin the real meeting happened
when the cameras was was sent
out and what the real agenda was that's
not for the world to know okay we as a
country need need to explain nothing to
anyone we as a country when we meet with
the leader of another country we discuss
things of mutual National interest
wherever our national interests converge
and align and when it comes to India and
Russia there is a significant
convergence of our national
interests so that's what would have been
discussed various aspects and factors in
that vicinity in that domain in that
direction what was said on camera was
for the benefit of the media and for the
benefit of the public the public needs
to be told something so we will say
something that makes some kind of sense
from the Public's perspective public is
dumb
right that's how it goes so Mr D has not
gone there to give any explanations to
Mr Putin Mr Putin is not silly he's not
stupid he knows exactly why Mr Modi went
to Ukraine Mr Putin knows better than
anybody else what Mr Modi was doing in
Ukraine and when he why why he met Mr Mr
zalinski Putin doesn't need any
explanations the discussion that would
have happened would have been about
future plans and convergence of mutual
National interest things that go beyond
Ukraine things that go in various other
directions so please please think beyond
the obvious please think beyond the
obvious think a little bit
more what you see on the screen is not
the entire world that is just meant for
public consumption what really happens
is something else entirely why don't you
people understand this please please
think
okay huh all right all right let's see
um Sindra says I've been using a a ton
of chat GPD and metas AI I can't find a
single Indian Source AI scared to lose
more to the white Masters collecting our
data data data more and more my views my
view is I've been I've been seeing this
for quite some time where the Indian AI
systems if you have any we don't see
it uh we've had some artificial
intelligence AI systems that have been
apparently developed by India CM or
whatever comes to mind and then it turns
out it's just a chat gbd
rapper so that's the kind of thing we do
uh maybe there are some AIS that are
being developed in India but for that I
mean you first of all need a tremendous
amount of data very large data sets um
that's something the Americans have
that's what Facebook meta Etc Twitter
Google they have tremendous amounts of
data I
mean oceans of data that's the first
thing you need to create an AI system
the second thing you need is a
tremendous amount of compute computing
power uh the highest end chips and tons
and tons of those so AI is the
cuttingedge technology of the day to-day
and it's the most expensive technology
of the day to-day today's
Ira uh so maybe that's something that
handicaps Indian companies if you have
Indian startups they typically don't
have the kind of money that you would
need to be able to compete with open AI
or meta or
whatever um but you've got to find
Solutions one of the things that is that
is hampering India is that we don't
produce our own semiconductors we are
dependent on the
Americans or whoever else you want to
create an N system you need Nvidia gpus
not CPUs gpus and the best the high the
best of the class right right and those
are really expensive and it's not like a
four or five gpus you need you you need
tens of thousands of those you to string
them together essentially and yeah
that's how you create an AI then you
have to
obviously fine tune it and so on so
forth so that's the problem we're facing
here we don't have our own semiconductor
manufacturing ecosystem we depend on
foreign countries that's what always
hamstrings India we have not ined Ed in
these things but now what to do you got
to do something about it the government
see the Indian government has access to
a tremendous amount of data all the data
that you can imagine for 1.4 billion
people so it has uh an ocean of data the
government of India are we quietly de
developing deploying an AI system of our
own I I don't know okay if it is being
done it may be done behind behind closed
doors or whatever but in the public
there is no uh Indian AI system and
that's kind of disappointing I mean we
need to have these systems of our own we
need to have these platforms of our own
a a homegrown AI system or or a family
or or different homegrown Indian AI
systems that are publicly available that
would be good to have uh systems that
can converse uh in Indian languages
native Indian languages indigenous
Indian languages all that we need and if
we don't do that then we're going to
just essentially abdicate our
sovereignty give away our sovereignty to
to the West
so that's the long and the short of it
and we do need to say do something about
this viom says why does Kamala Harris
call herself black rather than Indian
well look ethnically if you look at the
her her ethnic background she's 50%
Indian maybe 30 40% black and and about
some percentage whatever is left
probably white okay so her father was a
mixed race person mainly black but also
some White and her mom was Indian or is
Indian I'm not sure if her mom is alive
or not uh so she's mixed race she is 50%
Indian the the ma major component of her
ethnicity is Indian that's the dominant
component of her ethnicity but when it
comes to the US I mean if you're mixed
race you kind of look like you can pass
off as anything and she isn't definitely
not very fair skinned so for most
Americans who are not aware of her
background they would imagine that she's
black and these days um the black people
are kind of the dominant ethnic group in
the US at least apparently and she would
like to take full advantage of that so
um she's like like a chameleon she
switches from black to Indian depending
on the context so recently she TW
tweeted about something about her
grandmother being some something or
other okay and her grandfather being
some Fe Freedom Fighter which he was not
he was actually working for the British
so her Indian grandfather and
grandmother uh she tweeted something
about them and she said that her
grandfather was a freedom fighter when
he actually was a British civil servant
or something collaborator
essentially um so when it suits her she
will say that she's Indian but on every
other occasion especially when there's
no election anywhere in the in in the
distance
she she downplays her Indian ancestry
and plays up her black ancestry well
it's all about convenience that's what
politics is all
about
okay mlav says so we are importing corn
now for ethanol blending blending and
petrol also the government is forcing
20% blending by next year which will
cause rust in engines this is going to
end with a complete disaster I'm hearing
stories about this I'm not aware of what
what's really happening um ethanol
blending blending I think 10% is
something that we have been doing until
now uh not sure if 20% is
advisable but I I I I don't have
sufficient clarity about this because
I've not read this
up whether the technology exists to be
able to accommodate 20% ethanol ethanol
is essentially ethy alcohol right
methane ethane propane butane and
pentane hexane that's the that's the
alkane chain
um so ethy alcohol ethanol is is just
that's that alcohol that comes from
fermentation of organic product organic
materials sugar canes Etc corn whatever
you can just ferment that and produce
your industrial grid alcohol ethanol now
20% not sure if it's the right thing to
do I hear a lot of chatter about this
but I haven't really read up on this
whether 20% is good or whether it it's
going to create problems in
it will it create rust what what happens
when you when you combust alcohol does
it give off H2O probably H2O may be one
of the uh one of the um byproducts of
the
combustion uh
c um C2 H4 something and okay I don't
remember right now the chemistry but
yeah so uh I hope the government is
doing the right thing
uh just because you like a certain
technology doesn't mean you need to fo
it on the nation hopefully everything
has been has been studied properly and
everything is whatever is being
implemented is being implemented the
right way and if it is not then I hope
there is course correction but I don't
have the answers right now because I've
not read up on
this pram Sharma says is India planning
on bombing or interfering in Myanmar
Civil War well I I am not part of the
Indian
government so I'm not privy to what the
plans
are I have said that the solution to the
Manipur terrorism crisis lies outside
the borders of India and of
Manipur but uh if whatever the plans are
obviously there's they're not going to
announce them to the public and they're
not going to announce them to me so I
can't tell
you
um prum amales says why do Pakistan many
people claim to win the to have won the
wars of 65 71 Etc look when you have
lost multiple Wars it's it's
demoralizing it's depressing so then you
invent fictitious narratives that you
won the wars right uh so I don't blame
them for it I mean how depressing can it
be imagine that that you lost all the
wars so that's why right it's simple
it's just to cope with the with the uh
with the stress and with with the
depression that comes with uh having
lost all the
wars
um
okay
uh let's see what the questions we
have
um okay Aram Mana says is bricks
currency really going to happen to
counter the USD hemony
I don't know I mean uh the the recent
bricks the latest the last bricks Summit
was in South Africa I think it was last
year um about about roughly a
year 12 or 13 months before today
roughly 12 13 14 months before to day
and
um there was chatter before the brick
submit happened that bricks would
announce a bricks currency that would be
backed by gold in a basket of
commodities is but it did not happen and
India kind of said before the brick
Summit that we're not really interested
in in the sort of
currency and then the currency was never
announced and uh nothing major happened
after that when it comes to the bricks
currency any any potential bricks
currency this time the bricks Summit
will
happen soon
enough probably in October if I'm not
mistaken
and there's been no talk of a bricks
currency this
time so if it's going to happen maybe
it's not going to happen this time maybe
it's something that we planning for the
future maybe we planning it maybe we're
not planning it I'm not really sure the
point is if you want to counter the
hemony of the US dollar you have to do
it slowly gradually in a way that is
non-provocative because the Americans if
you if you come up with a currency
that's a direct competitors to theirs
it's it's going to provoke them and they
may take certain very harsh steps you
don't want that to happen you want to do
it slowly slowly gradually gradually
learn from the Chinese the Chinese are
Past Masters At This the salami slicing
me methodology so so I don't think a
bricks currency may happen anytime soon
but who knows maybe I'm wrong and
they'll announce it next month who knows
so um I think the the likelihood is less
but let's see how it goes let's see how
it goes uh
but yes eventually the world will kind
of slowly gradually move away from the
US dollar because it's a catastrophe
waiting to happen it's it's just a paper
currency held together by the threat of
force that's what it is the only thing
that keeps the US dollar
afloat is the US Global power projection
capability that's what keeps the US
dollar uh afloat as the uh Global
Reserve currency the moment that
hypothetically disappears nobody will to
use the US dollar and people may go back
to Gold based currencies gold backed
currencies or something so the the way
to end the hegemony of the US dollar is
not to put
out a Ral currency maybe it is maybe it
is but I think what what you really need
to do is is is challenge The Americans
on every other front that that really
needs to happen and and some currencies
may obviously slowly become more
relevant not the Euro Definitely Maybe
the rubal maybe the Yuan maybe hopefully
the rupe but we'll have to
see um class says why can't an elder
woman and younger man marry each other
well there is nothing in the law that
says that that an elder woman and a
younger man can't marry each other
there's nothing in in the law in India
that says you can't do that there's
nothing in the laws of the US Europe Etc
or or even Russia or whatever China I
guess there's nothing that says that a
woman Elder woman or younger man can't
marry each other so if you want to
please please go ahead and do that
there's nothing like that obviously in
society you you look historically what's
been what's been the the the purpose of
marriage as a social and cultural
institution the purpose of marriage has
been to
promote and protect monogamy so that
there is no Strife in society that's
number one and secondly to to have
stable families with multiple Offspring
so that Society continues to flourish
that's historically for the longest ever
time essentially forever that's been the
context and the reason why marriage
exists as a social
institution and for that to happen it
makes sense for both the partners the
husband and the wife the spouses to be
of similar
ages so that's why you typically expect
both Partners to be of roughly similar
age but there is nothing that says that
you can't have a 60-year-old woman and
and a 20y
old guy as as as husband and wife I mean
it's weird but it's not illegal so you
want to do that go ahead and do
it okay
um okay what else do we
have bti it says did bhat Singh meet
sarar I'm not aware I'm not aware I have
not studied bhat Singh I have not
studied sarar there are many historical
figures that I have not had the time to
study or not have had the inclination
thus far to study because you can't
study everything so I haven't read up on
bhat Singh's life history on saar's life
history on various other figures
probably did not interest me that much
I'm I'm sure they're all um colossal
figures in their own right but I haven't
come around to reading about them so I
don't know I don't know if bhat Singh
met
sarer in the largest larger context of
of the Indian Freedom struggle from
British
occupation we've had millions of Indians
who gave up their lives who were killed
brutally by the British but for some
reason we only remember a handful of
them sarer was not somebody who was
killed by the British who was he was
actually a freedom fighter who uh sought
to fight the British occupation in a way
that was very different from that of Mr
Gandhi and that is why Mr sarer is kind
of vilified today of course also because
he was a strong proponent of Hinduism
Hindu whatever you want to call it so
that's why he's V fight today but I
think he is a very relevant and very
important freedom fighter and we have to
look at his his perspective as well very
very
seriously that's about sarar about bhat
Singh clearly a very brave guy a very
brave man who gave up his life for the
country as did millions of others so I'm
not sure I mean you obviously I I am
would be the last person to take away
from what bhagat Singh did but let's
also remember the millions of others who
were no less
Brave why don't we remember those why
don't we have a day of remembrance for
those who the British killed in 1857 why
the hundreds of millions that the
British killed in the artificially
engineered famines the British killed at
least 10 million people in the in the
aftermath of the 1857 war of
independence in the decade after
1857 why don't we have a day of
remembrance for those people why do we
insist on remembering only a handful of
people I'm not saying that we should not
remember them I I mean that we should
remember all of our
people their sacrifices would were no
less than those than those of the ones
we remember so um we need to have a
bigger broader perspective of of our
freedom struggle of the real Freedom
struggle in which millions of our people
died we don't remember them and we
remember the the the people who are
portrayed as Freedom Fighters I'm not
saying bhat Singh and sarer are those
they were real Freedom Fighters no doubt
bhat Singh gave up his life sarer
suffered so much there are others who
are portrait as Freedom Fighters and so
on who were not really Freedom
Fighters well it's all about perspective
isn't it it's all about well what
narrative you
swallow uh abinash achara says what are
some of the countries where Indians
could settle and live a decent life in
their later years well hopefully India
hopefully Barat you know India has so
many problems you know and you I mean I
meet so many people in India who say my
city is the best city in the world yes
of course I have to travel I have to
commute 4 hours a day I know that I'm
struggling from from the time I wake up
to the time I sleep but no my city is
the best city in the world this is what
happens when you don't travel you should
travel you you should go to other
countries then you will realize how many
problems this country has I hope these
problems are solved many of most of the
problems are solvable we'll take time
we'll take some effort but every problem
is solvable whether it's the pollution
whether it's the corruption whether it's
the crumbling infrastructure whether it
is whatever else every problem can be
solved in this country the solutions are
pretty simple but hard to implement
without political will and political
will is difficult but so on so forth the
point
is I hope India is one of those
countries where Indians can settle and
live a decent life in their later years
well if you can obviously you have the
Western countries but these days there
is
increasing opposition to Indians in the
west but I'm sure most Western countries
are still quite decent and with good
people and obviously the the their infr
is top-notch the quality of life is
excellent uh so Indians historically
have wanted to go to the English
speaking countries either the us or the
UK or Australia some some would want to
go to New Zealand lots of Indians wanted
to go to Canada now Canada is no longer
an attractive destination unless you are
really uh well accomplished and you have
a hyping job or you are very rich uh but
yes if you if you have a lot of money
and if you have a great income and great
savings and Canada then any of the five
eyes countries anglosphere countries is
a decent place to go and settle down in
if you can speak various local European
languages then you can go to France
Italy Spain wherever
Portugal uh the Nordic countries are
under a lot of strife now because of
illegal immigration but well there you
have it and when it comes to uh other
countries let's say Eastern countries I
believe the UAE has good options for
settling down the UA is a first first
world country lots and lots of Indians
there the majority population is Indian
Indians and then you can think of
Nations like Thailand perhaps Thailand
also is a very welcoming country uh not
a first world country for sure slightly
better quality of life than India
actually significantly better quality of
life than India Thailand especially in
large cities and so on so forth they
have a problem in which in the sense
that uh most Thai people don't really
speak English which I actually admire
about them that they are not slave
minded
uh but it's it's culturally very
compatible with India Thailand they
essentially practice our culture in
their own
way if you know how to recognize it so
there's plenty of countries like that
where you could go and settle down and
have a decent life in your later years
the point is if you have sufficient uh
funds if you have sufficient resources
if you have sufficient savings then you
can have a decent life essentially
anywhere in the world so that's what is
more important than where you go
have sufficient wealth that you can live
a decent life good life
anywhere
um vishaka says how does a nuclear bomb
work is there any fictional weapon that
could be more powerful than a nuke that
is scientifically possible so I have a
video on this channel which is a crash
force on nuclear physics and it tells
you how nuclear weapons work let me try
and
uh bring that out over here so let's go
to let me share the
screen this is my channel let me search
for crash course crash course and you
will see not the philosophy crash course
but the nuclear physics and nuclear
weapons crash course which is about 303
minutes it's from 3 years ago uh if you
have 13 minutes to spare watch this
video it will tell you exactly how
nuclear weapons
work so nuclear weapons just to answer
it without go despite giving you that
reference as well nuclear weapons are of
two kinds fishion weapons mainly two
kinds there's more but mainly two kinds
fishing weapons and fishion fusion two-
stage weapons a fishing weapon it
essentially the principle behind it is
nuclear fishion neutrons split uh
uranium atoms and release a tremendous
amount of energy and that creates a CH
chain reaction that goes out of control
and that is your chain nuclear reaction
chain Chain Reaction which releases a
tremendous amount of energy in a very
short amount of time and that is your
standard nuclear fishion bomb but if you
want to take it a level further a whole
different uh Next Level thing
essentially like you say then you use
the initial fish explosion fish reaction
as the trigger for a fusion
react so you have duum pellets Etc
whatever that you fuse together and so
on and that that fusion reaction that
implosion creates a fishion re fusion
reaction that releases even more energy
than a fishion reaction that's a
thermonuclear hydrogen bomb or
thermonuclear fishion fusion bomb that's
the two major kinds of nuclear weapons
and the behind it you can study in
quantum mechanics uh fish is there any
fictional weapon that could be more
powerful than a nuke that is
scientifically possible yes yes
according to the laws of physics you can
have the most powerful weapon you can
imagine uh which is more powerful than a
nuke than a fusion nuclear bomb is uh an
antimatter
bomb so antimatter is like normal matter
but it has opposite charges opposite
quantum numbers
and you bring antimatter and matter
together they simply annihilate and
release Pure
Energy um
and gram for gram antimatter releases
way more energy than a nuclear fusion
reaction but antimatter is incredibly
scarse there's a very very small amount
of antimatter that has been produced
ever in all the colliders Etc that we
have in physics labs gigantic physics
Labs like the LHC large hydrin collider
maybe we have a few milligrams at most
that have ever been produced of
antimatter so if you were to price put a
put a put a price tag on antimatter it
would be a few trillion dollars per per
per kilo few trillion dollars per kilo
that's the kind of price it is but if
you have one kilo of antimatter it will
far give way more energy than a kilo of
uranium or plutonium so the most
powerful weapon you can imagine is an
antimatter weapon antimatter bomb that I
can think of right now I'm sure you can
possibly think of something worse maybe
a black hole weapon something but yeah
explosive power antimatter is I would
say the
ultimate
okay geopolitical du says does time
Prevail everywhere in the universe look
as far as we know time exists everywhere
in the universe but yeah the time here
is not the same as a time in a different
place this relativity of simultaneity
and the special relativity relativity
the laws of Relativity that apply
everywhere U so two events that appear
to be simultaneous to one Observer may
not be simultaneous for a different OB
observer in a different frame of
reference and all that I'll not go into
the details of Relativity but yes time
does exist as far as we know everywhere
in the universe we don't know what is
the origin of time we don't know what
time is we treat it as one of the
dimensions in the four dimensional
fabric of space time so from the
perspective of general relativity time
is one of the four dimensions length
breadth height and time that's the four
dimensional fabric of space time that's
the general relativity perspective time
is a dimension and the other most
successful theory is quantum mechanics
Quantum field Theory and in quantum
mechanics time is an external classical
parameter it's not something that
emerges from from quantum mechanics we
we don't know quantum mechanics can't
answer what time is and and from General
relativ perspective we also don't know
what's the origin of time or whatever
it's treated as one of the four
dimensions very successfully but yes
general relativity is one of the two
most successful theories that we have it
describes the universe at the largest
scales and it does so very successfully
and from that it appears it's pretty
clear that time seems to exist
everywhere Prevail everywhere in the UN
verse
right okay kushal kelker kushal kelker
says why would the US threaten Russia
with direct strikes from NATO when
Russia has the largest stockpile of
nukes why are they taking risks that
could lead to the third world war so
yeah recently the Americans uh I think
they've said that they will allow
Ukraine to launch strikes on Russia
Russia Direct stries on Russia with uh
NATO weapons uh long range missiles that
belong to
Nato and Putin very calmly said in
response to that that if uh Ukraine or
whoever uses NATO issued long range
missiles or whatever those those weapons
are against Russia the first hit the
first impact will be the beginning of a
direct war between Russia and NATO
he has made it very clear and please
understand one thing
puin has a long history in public life
and he doesn't Bluff from the time when
he was the the the manager or or
director of a city from that level from
from the level of City level boss all
the way to President of Russia he has
never
bluffed when he says something there is
waight to his words wait wait his words
have
meaning okay his words aren't empty
words like Kamala Harris or
whoever most politicians say a million
things and they don't mean 80 or 90% of
what they
mean Putin when he says something you
got to take it very seriously he doesn't
Bluff I think he likes to remind people
very often that I do not bluff if I say
something I mean it and I do it so I
think the West needs to be really really
careful if they have Ukraine launched
NATO weapons on Russia that's going to
be the the start of a direct conflict
between Russia and NATO and what could
Russia do in that case obviously it
won't start with a nuclear
exchange won't start like
that but Russia will
retaliate against NATO not against
Ukraine how could they retaliate against
against NATO for one one easy easy
target is they could take out one or two
the the the British the UK they have a
couple of uh
aircraft carriers
right those aircraft carriers don't have
defenses against Hypersonic weapons like
like the
kinjal oh no sorry not the kinal the the
Turon missile the Turon missile is a
Hypersonic cruise missile the fastest
missile in the
world and the the British aircraft
carriers have no defenses against that
maybe just to make a point the Russians
could take out one of the British
aircraft carriers maybe one maybe both
just to drive home a point look we're
serious here so I think the West needs
to be really really careful if they
allow if via Ukraine as a proxy they
launch NATO weapon strikes on Russia
that could lead to a very rapid and very
significant escalation of the conflict
which bypasses Ukraine now it's straight
between NATO and Russia which is
extraordinarily concerning
that that is like scary as hell so I
think the ERS is on the Americans not to
play around with the with this sort of
nonsense take a step back you back you
can't play with the future of the
world because if it devolves into a
nuclear exchange it's the end of the
world in
minutes believe me
H
okay Mya pendra says is the UK becoming
again a low economic country look the
right way to look at the UK is like this
the UK is a poor Nation attached to
London which is the one of the major
money laundering hubs of the
West that's how you actually should see
the UK so the UK is already a reasonably
poor country it produces next to
nothing it it doesn't have any relevance
in geopolitics international relations
it's a Third Rate world
power and the only thing that's going
for the UK is the city of London London
which is a major money laundering and
financial Hub that's the only thing
that's going for the UK so if London did
not exist the UK would nobody would care
about the UK essentially it wouldn't be
relevant in any way whatsoever without
London so that's the UK for
you harid J says who will lead the EU
into the next decade France or Germany
neither Germany is being dismantled as
we speak the economy uh is being trashed
the German economy Volkswagen is on the
verge of bankruptcy can you believe it
Volkswagen the iconic car manufacturer
one of the greatest car manufacturers
they are whoever is behind this
obviously it's the US is behind this
they are step by step dismantling the
German economy they started this by
cutting off Germany's access to cheap
Russian energy cheap Russian gas without
copious amounts of cheap energy no
economy can
work so uh Germany doesn't stand a
chance they have even shut down their
nuclear reactors they're going back to
Coal or I don't know what they're going
to uh Renewables and green energy please
that's not how it works so Germany seems
to be doomed now Germany is not going to
lead anybody anywhere and their their
demographics are been are being trashed
right now and when it comes to France
even the French demographics are under
tremendous amount of press because of
what's been going on and uh France would
like to have kind of an independent
foreign policy I've spoken about this
multiple times but can France lead
Europe into the next decade I don't see
France having the leadership for that I
don't see m m Emanuel ma is being a
great
leader does he really represent the
French people I mean his actions in the
past few days of obstructing democracy
uh don't do him any credit so he's not
really a leader that seems to have fr
French interests close to his
heart I don't know who he really works
for uh the world economic Forum or
whatever so even France I would love
France to do really well India and
France have a good
relationship and I would like to see
that go further of course but I don't
see even France being allowed to even if
they want to lead Europe into the next
decade I think Europe is being slowly
de-industrialized and and reduced to uh
irrelevance by The Americans
so I don't see anybody actually leading
the EU in the next decade maybe maybe
Poland is Poland a member of the EU
let's let's Google it very quickly is
Poland EU
member let's see probably it
is is Poland uh
EU country it is right yes since 1st May
2004 so maybe Poland Maybe be allowed
to to lead the EU in the next decade
let's see I'm not sure let's
see
um okay what other
questions so Khan says France has to
look Beyond culture and language and
address actual issues look the French
have a lot of things going for them
culturally uh it's all about
uh what is
it about sitting on past Laurels that
applies to all the entirety of Europe
they were Europe used to be great in the
past until World War I World War I until
the European Tribal wars that devastated
the whole of Europe and establish the us
as the principal power in Western
Europe so today Europe is like
Disneyland for the
Americans um they have these nice cities
well planted cities they have these
castles and these historical places that
the Americans and Chinese and whatever
else Indians sometimes come to visit and
that's how the European economy grows
the Europeans don't have any startup
culture they don't have any gigantic
Industries apart from a few that used to
exist in Germany they have a very
laid-back work culture they don't have
that that
drive that the Americans have um so that
applies to France as
well um so what historically has drawn
people to France is language and culture
L long Fran the culture French culture
French Cinema cema whatever else the the
the city of par beautiful city the most
romantic city in the world it used to be
until now I don't see people thinking
that way too much the architecture the
history all that but the actual issues
that plague let's say France first of
all it's immigration the demographics
are
are well there a demographic disaster
happen happening there they have allowed
in so much of
immigration in a certain
direction that they are facing a lot of
strife a lot of the immigrants who have
coming from North Africa are disaffected
maybe with good reason they feel like
they marginalized they feel like the
French don't see them as French they
feel like the French see them as
Outsiders but when you talk about the
north Africans you talking about Muslim
people okay and they are at least 10 15%
of French society now they're going
nowhere so how does France integrate
them can France even integrate them at
all they have the the immigrants the the
Algerian and North African immigrants
they they have this big chip on their
shoulder the French devastated their
homelands and they treat them as
Outsiders and all that so there is that
that's one of the actual issues the
economy isn't doing great the French
have good Industries they have the
defense industry they they they have
airus they have Rafal they have saf
which is the jet engine manufacturing
thing they have uh automobile industry
as well so they have good Industries but
they don't have the the drive that the
Americans have and the actual issues are
these so industrially and economically
the French aren't doing great they're
doing okay not great they have these
extremely dangerous demographic
issues um and of course they are a
member state of the EU as well as NATO
which means they
have suboptimal
sovereignty so these are some of the
issues the the French face I'm not sure
if they're in a position to extricate
themselves from this
mess and yeah that's the
deal arav Kosik says have you read the
autobiography of a yogi do you recommend
it to a
14-year-old I read it yes I have read it
I I read it more than 20 years ago I
have the book somewhere with me not here
not there either but I have it somewhere
the autobiography of Yogi I read it once
in my life and uh yeah do I recommend it
to a 14-year-old yeah certainly the
language is pretty simple it's not like
difficult language and maybe you will
gain something out of it maybe you will
gain inspiration maybe you'll
gain answers to spiritual questions or
whatever
so I would certainly recommend you read
it I think Steve Jobs recommended the
book didn't
he I think he gave a copy of that book
to everybody who attended his uh funeral
or something so if Steve Jobs recommends
it I think it must be a good book so I
would also say go ahead read it if
you're if you're curious about it it's
not a long read read you may be able to
read it in in a day or so depending on
your speed so yeah go for it read it you
may gain something significant from the
book ainash says why did Russia help
India um in the 1971
War why do Nations do what they do
generally Nations do whatever they do on
the geopolitical domain on the
geopolitical field out of national
interest out of their own National
interest out of self-interest so if
Russia helped India in 71 it helped
their it helped them further and Advance
their interests they did not want the
Americans see in 71 in this this in the
20th century during the Cold War era
India was a Russian Ally your teachers
and the media will say that we were a
non-aligned country that's
BS we claimed to be non-aligned but we
were a Russian Ally okay it's as as
simple as that India was on the Russian
side of the Cold War
divide so from Russia's perspective
India was a major asset for
them in the Asian theater in the in the
Asia in the in the Indian Ocean theater
in the Asia theater the second largest
Nation second most populous nation in
Asia definitely a prized asset and they
did not want
India to succumb to the Americans and
and and to lose a war
Pakistan they wanted India to
remain strong to a certain extent not
too strong but not too weak either so to
maintain that balance of geopolitical
power in the subcontinental region in
the Asia region they helped India in the
71 War because this was a conflict
between proxy conflict to some extent
between the Americans and
Russians the East pakistanis were
obviously a Us wasal in India you could
say was a was a Russian
Ally and they wanted to give the
Americans a setback that's why they
helped India in the 71 War out of
self-interest everything the that
happens in geopolitics happens out of
self-interest if two nations are friends
it's because friends from your
perspective it's because it makes sense
for them to be allies because it helps
each other in a mutually beneficial way
that's why you become friends there's
always interest in friendship in
geopolitics at least hopefully not so
much in life but probably in life as
well
okay okay McLovin has a great idea you
have more than 200 podcasts on YouTube
maybe we can take all the data and
create an AI Abit with whom we can
interact with maybe even even your
grandkids can yeah I'm sure it's
possible it's definitely possible I have
hundreds of hours of of uh
unfiltered uh interaction on YouTube
hundreds of hours of it uh more than 200
asket sessions roughly 90 minutes each
that's
2,000 minutes
18,000 18,000 minutes I don't know how
many hours that is but you can it's 300
hours
roughly uh and I have other podcast as
well so yeah hundreds of hours of of me
speaking
unfiltered on on on YouTube so and on on
a very wide range of topics history
geopolitics science I also have podcast
not podcast I have these videos you vog
videos which you may not be aware of in
which I've documented My fasting Journey
a couple of fasting Journeys water
fasting and other stuff so there's a
whole lot of content of me on the
internet on
YouTube uh you can certainly collate it
all together and create an AI version of
me from that whom anybody can interact
with the technology already does exist
so yeah it's certainly feasible for sure
certainly feasible for
sure okay Aram says is a colony on Mars
possible by 2050 what are the major
challenges a colony on Mars is possible
by 2050 depending based on the
capabilities that that SpaceX currently
has their most powerful rocket is called
the Starship right and it's capable of
of of
transporting several hundred tons of
payload to
Mars and it needs a few more tests
obviously but that's the thing about
SpaceX they they test their capabilities
very rapidly the first Starship was
tested and it it it took off and then
they had to detonate
it but it did well and then just a few
weeks or months later they tested it and
it for for much better so in a couple of
years they've done multiple tests and
each test has been Improvement on the
previous capabilities and Starship is
almost
there so they going to in the next
couple of years they will send a couple
of missions to to Mars unmanned missions
just to make sure that the rocket works
as expected and in this decade we're
going to have humans reaching the moon
that's what Elon Musk has tweeted now
maybe it's an optimistic very optimistic
projection maybe it's not
and if he does
send a rocket to bars in this decade
maybe 27 28 29 around that time that
rocket could have maybe 100 200 300
passengers with enough uh material and
payload to establish a small settlement
on Mars so you may have that by 2040
itself a small Mars
colony and then you send another 20
Rockets gets another 20 you know trips
you do and you can have a whole village
or town set up on Mars by by 2050 it's
definitely very much possible what are
the major challenges the major
challenges are probably the US
government will they allow Elon mus to
do everything that he wants he certainly
has a technological capability to do
that uh the the the rocket is definitely
almost proven it will be proven properly
in a couple of years if it does a couple
of trips uh as expected without any any
problems without any glitches to Mars
then you're going to have human human U
uh human space flights to Mars so I
think the major impediment could be the
US government whether they come and
stand in his way and create problems for
him apart from that I don't see any
major challenges unless there are any
any setbacks in the development of the
Starship rocket I don't see any major
challenges apart from
that okay
shirat says how far are we from
achieving fusion power plants I mean
fusion power plants is is
is um essentially it's controlled
nuclear fusion so there are two kinds of
nuclear reactions exothermic nuclear
reactions fishion and fusion fishion is
when you split an atom split the nucleus
of an atom that's what that releases a
tremendous amount of energy that's
nuclear fici and you can have a chain
reaction of nuclear ficient which gives
off which essentially if it's not
controlled it's a nuclear bomb if you
control it using du duum rods and
whatever else then it's a nuclear react
nuclear power plant a fish and power
plant so most nuclear reactors use the
fishing reaction whether it's uranium or
plutonium uh some you have breeder
reactors which produce more fuel than
they consume and so on so for that's
that's ficient Fusion is when you fuse
two atoms you fuse let's say two atoms
of hydrogen together which gives you
a a helium atom hel helium nucleus and
that if you able to do that squeeze them
together and Infuse them that gives off
way more energy than a fishion reaction
so Fusion is much more
energetic the energy output is way more
than a efficient reaction but to fuse an
atom to get two atoms together requires
incredible amounts of energy so to spend
money you to to earn money burn money
first right that sort of thing so that's
the deal with with fusion and we
certainly can achieve Fusion on this
planet thermonuclear weapons are that
uncontrolled Fusion if you want to see
what a fusion reaction looks like look
in the direction of our parent star the
sun don't look at it directly it'll burn
your retinas but the sun is an example
of a fusion reaction that's happening in
real time I mean you're seeing it 8
minutes 8 minutes something delayed but
there you have it so to achieve
controlled Fusion is extremely difficult
it's proven almost impossible thus far
but there are certain experiments that
are ongoing in certain parts of the
world there's one in China there's one
somewhere
else in which we seem to be inching
closer and closer to achieving sustained
and controlled
Fusion you usually use magnetic
confinement of the plasma it's plasma
that you're trying to fuse to together
and you you use magnetic confinement a
device like a Tokamak or something
similar and you hope to achieve fusion
with that so I think that's the uh
approach that's been used and I don't
think we are very far
from possibly having controlled Fusion
on Earth maybe within a decade or two we
may we may be able to do that maybe
sooner who knows
okay Krishna Singh asks an interesting
question if India
somehow lost a war with China in the
future will it create a chance to
implement Hindu ideology one party
system in India because democracy is
killing the potential of Indians that's
a rather interesting question you ask so
consider this entirely fictitious
entirely hypothetical
scenario okay completely hypothetical
don't don't hate me for for for doing a
thought experiment a experiment so in
this imaginary
experiment India loses a war to China
and India comes under Chinese Dominion
domination control whatever you want to
call it now the first question is will
the Chinese in such a completely
fictitious ridiculous hypothetical
scenario will the Chinese want to occupy
India
militarily I think it's it's a Fool's
errand the chines would not want to in
this imaginary hypothetical scenario
they would not want to occupy India
militarily what they would want in this
imaginary scenario is to place a puppet
government in power in Delhi that will
control the country and be a vasal to
the Chinese Communist party that's what
the Chinese would I would most likely
want in this imaginary
scenario so what kind
of what kind of puppet government will
they install in this imaginary scenario
they will install a government that is
very similar to the one that they have a
one party system political parties in
this imaginary scenario will be B
democracy in this imaginary scenario
will be banned look the
Chinese have often criticized India very
strongly okay they do they've been doing
it for quite some time what are the
criticisms they have of India one is
that India in their words is is
is it's it's a in the in the in from the
Chinese perspective India is a slave of
the West and a lap dog of the West
what do they mean by this they mean that
we are so deeply mentally and colonized
in various ways that we are still
carrying on the system that was used to
colonize us the system of governance
that the colonizers imposed upon us when
they were occupying India we have
continued that since 47 like a good
slave so that's what the Chinese
criticize and their criticism is
entirely
Justified that's one that's one
criticism the Chinese have of India that
we are slaves of the West and lap dogs
of the West the second criticism that
they have is that there's too much
democracy in India and they use India as
an example of what happens when you have
democracy a country that doesn't work
that's Paralyzed by a thousand different
forces pulling it in a thousand
different directions and the end end
result is inertia that's what India is
India has never risen to its potential
past whatever years since 47 so these
are the two Chinese criticisms of India
and these are valid criticisms but we
get upset about it try and understand
what they're trying to say that the
Chinese don't hate India they are
contemptuous of India because we have
not
decolonized they don't respect India
because we are
still like good slaves continuing to
whip ourselves after the Masters have
gone so if the Chinese in this imaginary
scenario win a war against India and
they install a puppet government in
India it's going to be a one party
system it's going to be authoritarian
there's going to be no
democracy will it be a Hindu
system maybe it will the Chinese have no
issue with
Hinduism the Chinese have absolutely no
issue with Hinduism the Chinese have an
issue with
secularism they don't believe in
secularism have the Chinese imp
secularism in
China they tolerate Buddhism and the
indigenous Chinese culture and religion
these days in the past the CCP was
extremely harsh on Buddhism and all
Religion Today the CCP kind of promotes
Buddhism as an indigenous Chinese
religion they claim that Buddhism is IND
indigenous to China because it's been in
China for 2,000 years so now it's an
indigenous Chinese religion no longer
Indian it's it's it's Buddhism with
Chinese characteristics so the Chinese
promote Buddhism they they allow people
to practice whatever uh religion they
want if they want to most Chinese are
still atheists but India is not a
atheistic country and the Chinese will
definitely not allow in this imaginary
hypothetical scenario uh they will not
allow this nonsensical secularist
ideology to continue they probably will
be okay with with a Hindu
government maybe they will they will
install a wasal state a one party
authoritarian regime which is a Hindu
regime which actually may be a better
thing for India than what we have today
I am not by any means recommending that
India should uh lose to China in a war
or any such thing I'm just saying that
that's what they may actually do in this
completely hypothetical imaginary
scenario uh but yes the Chinese
criticisms of India are very valid India
has too much democracy which means that
India has the kind of democratic system
that is in equal to India's interests
and secondly India is in their words a
slave of the West and a lapt of the West
which means that we have never
decolonized and that's what that's
something they find
contemptible
okay they just asks what would it take
for the US dollar to collapse for the US
dollar to collapse the US power
projection ability in the world should
collapse only then will the US dollar
collapse what is the thing that
underpins the US dollar and ensures that
the US dollar Remains the global Reserve
currency it is the threat of US military
intervention that ensures that every
country accepts the us as the
international Reserve
currency uh whenever there's been an
attempt to
float an alternative currency to the US
dollar it's being met with disaster
mamar Gaddafi tried to float an African
currency based um backed by
gold and you know what happened to him
you know what happened to his country
Saddam Hussein tried to do something
similar not not exactly a you a separate
currency but he had a lot of gold and he
to tried to S up to the US he was wiped
out we know what happened to him so
whenever there's been a challenge to the
US
dollar it's been met with extreme brutal
force so that's why the US dollar
Remains the world's Reserve currency
it's because of the US ability to
intervene militarily anywhere on the
surface of the planet at 60 minutes
notice they can do that that's why the
US dollar Remains The Reserve currency
so what would it take for the US dollar
to collapse what what it will take is
the collapse of the US Global power
projection capability which means the
collapse of the superpowers status of
the
US why does the US have this Global
power projection capability because they
have more than 800 extra territorial
military bases spread all across the
world extr territorial means outside of
US Territory more than 800 that's why
the US dollar is the world's Reserve
currency so that's the cause and effect
thing davat Singh says how do physicists
explain time is it totally explained or
is there some great mystery behind it
there are two ways in which we explain
time or we incorporate time in our
theories in general relativity or in
special
relativity let's talk about general
relativity in general relativity time is
one of the four
dimensions one of the four dimensions of
the fabric of the universe the fabric of
the universe is called SpaceTime it is
the stage on which or within which all
events in the universe take place this
fabric has four dimensions length
breadth height and time so time is one
of the four fundamental
dimensions
and SpaceTime itself is curved it is it
is Warped by the presence of mass so the
presence of mass curves SpaceTime not
just space but also time and the
curvature of space time tells Mass how
to move that's the the interplay that's
the dance
between massive objects and the fabric
in which they reside space time so from
the perspective of general relativity
time is one of the four fundamental
dimensions in quantum mechanics which is
the other major Theory time is an
external classical parameter which does
not emerge from the theory it's external
to the
theory so quantum mechanics doesn't
quite explain what time is it just
treats it as an external parameter a
non-quantum non-quantized parameter a
classical
parameter uh
so that's how you see time from these
two big perspectives the two most
successful theories in physics are
quantum mechanics or Quantum field
Theory and general relativity and they
have these two different uh ways of
treating time but do we have a theory
which explains what time actually is
where it emerges from is is time an
emergent property of the universe or is
time something that's embedded in the of
the universe like general relativity
says or is time something that is
external to the universe just like it's
an external parameter and quantum
mechanics or or is it like I said an
emerging property of of quantum form or
something from qft Quantum not from qft
from Loop quantum gravity or something
like that I mean are there atoms or
molecules of time or is time something
that is simply a construct of the human
consciousness of human of of of of yeah
human consciousness is it something that
we perceive but doesn't actually exist
but then how is it there in general
relativity um or is time something that
is a consequence of quantum decoherence
or Quantum dis or quantum entanglement
we don't quite have the answers but from
the perspective of the two major
theories I have explained in brief what
time is and as of today that's how we
see time from the perspective of quantum
mechanics and the perspective of general
relativity but yes there are big open
questions and that is what makes time
one of the biggest mysteries and the
most fascinating questions in
physics
okay Shar Narayan says can you please
explain why doesn't India claim the
traditional boundaries of the princely
state of Kashmir when the king had has
accepted Kashmir as part of
India we do claim uh the whole of uh
Kashmir as part of India uh some of it
is currently temporarily under under
under Pakistani occupation which is
Pakistani occupied Kashmir let's go to
the map
briefly and speak about that so if you
take a look at the map uh if you look at
the Indian version of Google Maps it
shows the official uh map of India but
if you open Google Maps from out out of
India it will show dashed lines and it
will show parts of this as disputed
territory and all that even here if you
if I click over here it says unavailable
it doesn't say India
so uh India does claim all of this for
example skardu is currently under
Pakistani occupation and then you have
some parts of Kashmir that have been
seeded by Pakistan to China and some
more parts of Kashmir apparently India
doesn't claim them yeah uh north of the
shakum river and all that and so on the
point is this uh you can make claims but
you have to actually hold the territory
uh simp simply putting something on
paper doesn't make it yours you have to
establish facts on the ground that
something India needs to
learn so
uh one of the biggest truths in
geopolitics is that no border no
boundary is
permanent everything changes over time
boundaries keep changing keep evolving
keep expanding and
Contracting nothing thing is ever
permanent so today's boundaries are not
necessarily the boundaries of the next
two decades in 2050 you may have a
different set of boundaries in 2075 you
probably will have a very different set
of boundaries in Asia and so on and so
forth it's always going to keep
changing
India India should claim whatever has
traditionally been its but if you want
to go back to that as to what has
traditionally been Indian Territory then
we have to then we would have to claim a
b border with with uh with Tajikistan
because just 800 years ago when chingis
Khan crossed over from Central Asia into
India during his quasm campaign the
boundary between India and Central Asia
was was about 80 kilometers from the
current Afghanistan Tajikistan
boundary in in Tajikistan so look
uh what you can claim realistically is
what you actually can hold on to but of
course historically India has been much
larger uh so that's a
deal you have to establish facts on the
ground merely putting things on paper
look anybody can do it anybody can say
tomorrow sitting in whatever City that I
am now the president or the king of this
IND dependent country I can declare
independence I mean anybody can do such
a silly thing you know for declaring
independence on paper or claiming
himself or herself the the ruler of an
imaginary Kingdom with so and so
boundaries on the map it's it's an
exercise in
fertility you have to establish facts on
the
ground and uh whatever India can do uh
so if you if you want to claim more
territory you to get more powerful you
have to be able to actually hold on to
the territory and acquire the ter
territory first of
all
okay Nik jaman says how can when can we
expect an increase in the strength of
our passport and how optimistic are you
on the cic connector growth here look
what do you mean by the strength of a
passport essentially the strength of
your passport means how many countries
can you travel to without requiring a
Visa and and if you look at that the
rankings India is not in the top 100 I
if I'm not mistaken India is about
ranking is about 110 or something last
time I had seen or last I recall you can
check it out I'm not going to open that
uh rankings over here right now so
India's ranking isn't very great India
has access to about 60 plus countries uh
where it does not require a Visa or you
can just get a visa on arrival for
example if you go to Thailand you can
just go with your passport you don't
need to apply for a Visa and you go to
the airport and they'll stamp your your
your passport with a Visa once you
arrive there so you don't need to
pre-apply for a Visa you'll get a visa
and they'll just because you're Indian
they'll give you visa on arrival the
same applies to Nations like uh Iran
nowadays does morus need a visa I think
they give you visa on arrival so does
Sri Lanka I'm sure so there's a bunch of
countries that give India visa on
arrival but if you are from Japan if
you're from Singapore you have Visa free
access to more than 180 more than 190
countries
more more or less so that's the kind of
strength those countries have so how
come a small nation like Singapore has
such incredible Visa free access to
almost all nations how come uh a nation
like Barbados or or whatever small
nation how do they have access to so
many countries so generally to have more
countries give you Visa free access you
need to be a country with a high GDP per
capita that way they're pretty sure that
you your your citizens will not try to
stay in their country illegally after
the expir of their Visa or without
getting Visa so if you are a prosperous
rich country then it makes sense for
your citizens after visiting whatever
country to go back home because your
home country is more prosperous than
most of the countries so it's generally
High income Nations and and First World
countries that have strong passports
that's how it works because other
countries know that their citizens won't
overstay their welcome essentially they
have enough they have enough waiting for
them back home so to increase the
strength of your passport you have to
become a higher income country that's
what it is so India needs to increase
its GDP which will lead to a
corresponding increase in its GDP per
capita India will need to uh become a
more livable country country with better
living standards as that happens not
only will uh the GDP per capita increase
but India's GE political relevance
overall globally will also increase
because of its increasing GDP which will
give it stronger relations with other
countries it will make India a more
attractive partner more and more for
other countries which will induce them
to more countries to give India visa and
arrival facilities or VISA free access
facilities so to make a long story short
to increase the strength of your
passport you have to increase the
strength of your economy you to grow
your GDP that's the simple answer how
optimistic am I on the semiconductor
growth here I am reasonably optimistic
that in 20 years will be one of the
major semiconductor
Powers not the next two years not the
next 5 years probably not even the next
10 years but I am optimistic that in the
next 20 years we'll be one of the major
semiconductor manufacturing countries
and hopefully in 10 years we'll be a
reasonably strong country in this domain
I am pretty
optimistic okay
ding Johan says what who is the real
power behind the us if not the
government their military
bureaucracy the
government uh look what what you're
asking is what
goes what matters in geopolitics is a
nation's hard power not soft power now
what is hard power hard power is a it's
it's a number of factors and all of
those taken together
gives you a hard power score one is the
size of your land area second is the
size of your population third is your
total GDP annual GDP fourth is your
military expenditure per year uh the
fifth is the number of nuclear weapons
you have the sixth is your your power
projection capabilities the seventh is
your uh energy self-sufficiency and so
on so forth all of that taken together
if you add up and you create a secret
source of out of it it throws out a
number number for each country just a
number and that's your hard power score
so the US is way ahead of everybody else
in hard power so that's the real power
okay so that is the how the US hard
power score is calculated so it's not
the size of the land area that makes the
US a super power it's not the size of of
the the size of the economy definitely
matters the size of their military
expenditure definitely matters the
number of newes really
matters but what makes them a superpower
is their power projection capabilities
so all of that is the hard part now the
question is who is the real power behind
the us if not the government military
bureaucracy well whoever controls the US
president is the real Power by now it's
very clear that Biden was never running
the country he's on vacation right now
he's wearing a red Maga hat these days
the Donald Trump hat for whatever reason
is clearly not running the country the
president of the US he he's essentially
irrelevant now is Kamala the vice
president Kamala haris she is she
running the country she's also not
running the country so who's running the
country somebody is in all these years
since 2020 somebody has been running the
country not Biden not Kamala Harris
somebody has been so whoever that is is
the real power is it the military is it
the bureaucracy is it whatever I think
it's what they
call the US establishment which is a
combination of the military industrial
complex the military establishment in
the foreign policy establishment and
whoever is the real power handed so I
don't have the actual answers I would
not even hint at what the actual answer
could be but the small number of people
that probably
is running the country and probably even
owns the
country okay VII man says my parents
asked me to consider marriage proposals
from abroad but I can't breathe without
B they don't force me but don't we don't
leave when our mother needs us what
would you advise on
this oh well
um uh
look what I would tell you is that you
have to do what is in your own best
interests you were not
born you to ask yourself what was the
purp what's the purpose of your
existence were you born so that you can
sacrifice your happiness and make other
people happy other people
who unfortunately want be with with you
for the for the entirety of your life
the only one person who will be with you
for the entirety of your life is
yourself you are permanent everybody
else will come and go even the closest
of people they won't be around forever
possibly okay this is just the harsh
reality of life you to face it
so at the end of the day you have to be
happy in life otherwise your life will
be miserable Your Existence will be
miserable and just to make somebody
happy temporarily if you make a huge
compromise in your with your
life then you will spend the rest of
your days
unhappy and then what will happen is
that slowly secretly you will start
feeling bitterness for the per for the
people for whom you made the
sacrifice I would say do what is best
for yourself in some things you have to
be
selfish so your parents want you to
study study very hard get good marks do
all that sure it's good for you also but
if they are insisting that you marry
somebody from a different country and
you don't want that then you have to
draw the line
there tell them I'll marry a good guy
but I don't want to go to so and so
country I'll do it here you have to
respect my my my my
choice um maybe they think that you will
have a better life abroad and so on so
forth and whatever I'm sure there are
they have their own considerations and
perhaps with their Superior with their
greater experience they may understand
the world better than
you so and I'm sure that they don't mean
to make you unhappy and they think that
eventually you will see that it was the
right choice maybe they think that way
but there Comes A Time in your life when
you have to make your own
choices and I would say that if you
really genuinely feel that it will make
you miserable for the rest of your life
then I would say that draw a line and do
what is what you know is best for
yourself that's what I would say and
explain to them that I it's not I'm not
trying to hurt you or hurt your feelings
it's just that I I can't do that okay so
that's what I would say but at the end
of the day it's your decision don't tell
them that abijit cha said this I'm doing
this but please put yourself
first especially in cases like this
which can affect the rest of your entire
life all right ma'am all the best I I
really wish you the best in
this okay
um okay vishak n says if you were in
control of National Defense what kind of
weapons would you develop and
manufacture for Army Navy and Air Force
to make India strategically powerful in
the Indian subcontinent okay that's a
great question what would I do if I were
if I was in charge of National Defense
look how do
you measure a government's
performance how do you quantify a
government performance when it comes to
what it has done for National Defense
you ask yourself a very simple set of
questions H in
2014 how many fighter planes did bhat
have 2014 and today in 2024 how many
fighter planes does bhat have what has
been the Delta X
plus or minus how many have increased or
decreased that's one way of looking at
it second question how
many naval warships of various kinds did
Barat have in 2014 how many do we have
today how many submarines did Barat have
in 2014 how many do we have today how
many Attack Helicopters how many
transport helicopters and so on so forth
you can do that and then you can see the
difference that's how you see how a
government has performed in the field of
Defense how they have they done a good
deal for India now what would I
do I believe
that you know I I I understand the
ground reality that we are not currently
a nation that can manufacture jet
engines so the first thing I would do is
I would anyhow acquire jet engine
technology I would buy beg borrow or
steal jet engine technology any jet
engine ideally you you buy
it if it doesn't work you borrow or beg
it or you steal it I don't care doesn't
matter National def National interest
comes first above everything else above
ethics above morality above everything
else National interest comes before
everything else so acquire jet engine
technology is the first thing I would do
second thing I would make a truckload of
of manufactur truckload of the of the
thees fighter
planes and uh manufactur a whole bunch
of suo whatever whatever technology we
have see look quantity has a quality of
its own we may not have fifth generation
fighter planes the the technology right
now we are in the process of developing
that but uh I would certainly insist and
and and completely properly fund the
development of the of the of the uh AMC
of fighter plane the advanced medium
combat aircraft the fifth generation
fighter plane in the next 10 years I
would definitely fund that and make sure
it the time timeline uh it's all on
track that's what I would do I would um
have large quantities of whatever
aircraft we can manufacture I would have
the manufactured because we need numbers
we need numbers so maybe 100 200 thees
fighter planes maybe 100 more suo if
required by 200 Rafal we need numbers we
need numbers very important so that's on
the uh and I would I would have all
kinds of drones developed
loitering Munitions high altitude medium
medium altitude drones long endurance
hail maale drones uh loitering drones um
those kamikaza drones all kinds of
drones need to be developed drones that
can work in tandem synchronized drones
you know that can operate in swarms
swarms of 2,000 5,000 10,000 those kind
of drones I would have those develop
it's not that difficult to develop that
the iits could be red into that for this
matter they have we have very good
scientists and Engineers
there that's what I would do I would
emphasize on artillery you know
indigenous artillery artillery howt Serv
and so so and things like that missiles
cruise missiles you need a big stockpile
of cruise missiles and other kinds of
missiles maybe 10,000 20,000 you need
for a proper extended war in case you
are in one in a war
uh
um what
else like light arms Machine Guns Etc
instead of importing them from abroad I
would have them manufactur in India I'm
sure we have good prototypes that have
been developed in India so that's what I
would do and then I would very strongly
focus on the Navy lots of new warships I
would focus on once again quantity over
quality I would not say that use bad
quality I would say that you know put
out large numbers of Warships one
warship one class of Warship that is EXT
ordinarily deadly but kind of under
regged is the missile boat a light cheap
boat on which you can put 203 brahmas
missiles and you fill the ocean with
those that can completely be a game game
changer it can turn the the the the
Indian Ocean region
into an Indian
owned piece of Maritime real estate so
that is of course depends on the
endurance and the the endurance of the
boats but then you also need submarines
I would say a nation like India needs
100 submarines all of this costs a
tremendous amount of money but we have
the
money so these are some of the things I
would
do and I would develop icbms genuine
icbms not not a 10,000 kilometer range
or a 20,000 kilomet range ICBM just to
have that in the bank that's some of the
stuff I would do apart from others and I
would obviously take a look at the
nuclear weapons stockpile as well and we
probably need some tweaking in that as
well
perhaps
yeah uh yes ma'am you're you're very
welcome okay o says the meaning of life
according to me what's the meaning of
life I have no idea look um you I mean
it's not like I have no idea it's that
the mean the answer to the meaning of
life
exists at so many different levels at a
spiritual level at a religious level a
pH philosophical level at a at a
personal level at a societal level at
the cultural level and and and so much
more but how would
I um how would I express
this how would I communicate
it um the meaning of life what the
purpose of life what's the purpose of
life look the purpose of life in my
opinion you know you can have a
different interpretation or a different
answer for this from my
perspective if one day it's going to be
that I'm it's my last day right on this
planet in in this existence so on that
last day if I do the calculations and
the tallying and if I if I find that I
have given more to society than I've
taken from society then I'll be I'll die
a happy guy I'll say yes I've done my
part so from my perspective the purpose
of life is to give more to society than
you take from society that's the purpose
of life that's what what would make me
happy and the meaning of life is
is I think it's it's to take it's to
take on challenges and do do something
good do something fun something
interesting not something boring not
something routine do something different
be different do something different you
know change the course the trajectory of
the universe in some small way that's
the meaning purpose of life whatever you
want to call it contribute something to
society something meaningful something
positive not something not something
negative right that's how I see
it
okay uh what
other okay viur says will Africa come
out of the shadow of the colonial Powers
not anytime soon soon Africa is too far
gone it's been totally destroyed by the
colonialists it is still deeply
colonized almost directly colonized kind
of
indirectly um look we in India are
talking about decolonization we are
trying to figure out how to decolonize
if some of us do want to in Africa it's
still colonized by
proxy most African nations are run by
puppet governments that serve foreign
Masters Western Masters so Africa is
still colonized you know technically we
are taught that the era of colonization
ended after the world war world wars
that is a Lie the nature of colonization
changed after the world wars now it was
implicit colonization it was
colonization by proxy so the Western
Powers no longer have boots on the
ground in Africa they no longer have
soldiers on the ground in Africa after
the
60s but they have installed
wasal they've installed puppet
governments they've installed proxy
governments they've installed client
dictators who work on their behalf and
at the end of the day on the ground the
real reality is still the same the
nation is still colonized so I don't
know when it will happen it may take
another Century or so by which time
Africa will be completely devoid of
resources completely
devastated so that's how it works the
greatest sin in geopolitics is weakness
the greatest sin is defeat
okay mcloven says have you watched any
the movies I'm sure I saw a you have
watched a few of his movies as a
kid uh off late I haven't seen any but I
do remember the guy and I do remember
watching some movies aland Jean Paul
Belmondo I used to watch his movies Kine
denve Louis theun many French
French actors directors and much more
French Cinema used to be really
interesting I'm not sure how it is today
used to be really interesting back in
the day 20th century so I'm sure I've
watched a few of his movies as a
kid and harid I have answered this
question about an hour and a half
ago uh Muhammad ismile says what are
your thoughts on the declining white
population in the US is this accurate
yes so what's happening is that there is
population there's what they call Race
mixing happening
um there's a lot of white women
apparently who are having a
uh who are having children outside of
marriage with black
men and it looks like in the next couple
of decades uh there's going to be more
mixed race children who will be born in
the US compared to white children and by
2050 maybe the white people pure you
know unmixed white race people ethnicity
people may become a minority maybe
before that so it is certainly happening
there seems to be
um um promotion of race mixing or
whatever they call call it promotion of
that happening in a variety of subtle
ways in in
in cultural depictions and mainstream
media and whatever else whoever is
behind this whatever they're trying to
do it's up to them it's not not my
business not our business um what
happens the US is is their business but
yes it is indeed accurate so U
definitely by the end of the century I
think there may be very few actual uh
unmixed White ethnic ethnicity people
left in the
US well it is what it
is okay what else do we
have Shashank says why did we not adopt
a presidential system after Independence
well it's because our so-called
uh uh founding fathers like some people
allegedly call them they decided they
wanted a complete slave like copy of the
British
system so uh we have this uh what is it
called um constituent assembly and all
that right a bunch of people got
together who were elected through the
through the 1946 elections in which only
133% of the adult uh Indian population
was allowed to vote so it was a
completely illegitimate and democratic
election held under foreign occupation
and these people were the elected
representatives of those assemblies and
some were nominated directly by princely
states which were mostly puppets of the
British occupiers so that was the
constitu assembly and those that bunch
of people they decided to draft a
certain kind of cons ution and adopt a
certain kind of system and the system
they adopted was the Westminster system
which is a copy of the British system
House of Lords is the Upper House of
Parliament The House of the commons is
the lower of House of Parliament and the
overall head of government is the king
or the queen so in India we had the
rajas SAA to approximate the House of
Lords and the Lo SAA to to approximate
the House of Commons and because we have
done away with monarchy we have wiped
out our our kings and queens that's why
we put
puppet a
ceremonial post called the president of
India at the very top complete nonsense
why why do we need to emulate the
British system this A system that
developed over a thousand years on a
small island in the Atlantic Ocean it's
eminently unsuitable for a civilization
State a subcontinent sized Nation as
ours that's what these these people
decided they decided this
undemocratically they did not represent
the people of India
so that's why we adopted this
Westminster parliamentary system instead
of a presidential system or whatever
else essentially the British did they
they orchestrated this very nicely they
made it look like it was a democratic
process and today most Indians believe
that these the constituent assembly came
from the 1946 elections so it's
Democratic you I just don't have any
polite words to to utter here an
election held under foreign occupation
in is an illegitimate
election if Hitler held an election in
France during his occupation of France
in the 40s 1940s would you consider that
a legitimate
election so how can you consider the
1946 election which the British held
under British occupation to be
legitimate that's number one and
secondly less than 13 133% of the
eligible Indian adult population was
allowed to vote in the election so once
again it doesn't represent the Indian
population and how can you then consider
the constituent assembly as a legitimate
representation of the aspirations and
hopes of the people of India it's a
complete farce it's a joke and they came
up with this Constitution and then they
imposed it upon India undemocratically
the constitution of India has never been
ratified by the people of India what
does it mean it means the people of
India have never been given the
opportunity
to accept or reject this
document there should be a democratic
vote referendum here's the Constitution
read it do you accept or reject vote Yes
or No that's how it should be done in a
genuine democracy India is not a genuine
democracy there you have
it
okay why are some questions being
repeated so so so often I mean I
answered some of these
questions um okay
um what
else okay Jack Richard says what's the
possibility of NATO missiles deployment
inside Russian territories and Putin's
threat you
saying what does it mean that NATO
missiles will be deployed inside Russian
territory it deploy do you know the
meaning of
deployment here's the
map it means that the launchers will be
inside Russian territory for that to
happen NATO has to occupy actual Russian
territory it's
impossible because the moment Russian
territory comes under threat of foreign
occupation the Russian nuclear Doctrine
says Russia can use nuclear
weapons so that is a red line that NATO
simply can't cross without crossing the
nuclear threshold so there is no
possibility of NATO missiles being
deployed inside Russian territory
absolutely no possibility what
whatsoever what seems to be possible
right now is that Ukraine May launch
NATO missiles on Russian territory from
within Ukraine that's a possibility but
that would invite significant
retaliation significant retaliation very
very high retaliation from Putin and
that are you stupid I mean what are you
doing NATO seriously
okay have you watched the show The
Diplomat I haven't watched the show The
Diplomat um I hear it's a good
show uh but I haven't watched it I don't
really get the time to watch shows I
would love to watch some stuff on
TV but I haven't had the time to see it
but I've heard it's
good uh
okay what other questions do we
have davat Singh says will atheist India
be more successful in the future than
the religious one in the past and
atheist India will be a nation of idiots
and fools unfortunately because atheists
unfortunately are very low IQ
people I would not generalize it like
that
but you know what does it mean to be an
atheist atheists say that God doesn't
exist there is no Divine there is no
Supernatural there is nothing that is
not explained by science that's what
they claim everything is science
everything is the material world
everything is what we observe there is
no God there is no Divine there is no
such thing that's what the claim so what
they're essentially claiming is that
they know they have complete 100 100%
understanding and knowledge of
everything in the universe that's the
claim they are making now do you know
that we understand less than 5% of the
universe everything we see in the
universe it's less than 5% of the mass
of the universe mass energy of the
universe every Star every nebula every
Galaxy every point of light that we see
in the entire universe all of that added
together is less than 5% of the mass
energy of the universe 95% of the
universe is unknown it is dark about 25%
is dark matter about 70% Dark Energy we
have the least idea of what these things
are so when you understand less than 5%
of the universe how can you claim that
you know
everything that is the most
ridiculous claim a person can make that
I know there is no God I know there is
no this there is no nothing I know
everything is just
science so that's why I say that
atheists are really silly people and if
you have a nation of atheists then it's
a nation of people with very constrained
brains and imaginations and such a
nation is doomed to
failure and you need religion and
culture to give your Society a moral and
ethical framework which atheism simply
can't give you and you need religion and
culture to give most people hope without
which they they are clueless and lost in
the world so an atheistic India will be
a disaster it will be a failure it is
doomed to fail you want a an that is
grounded in its civilizational and
cultural and religious ethos that's what
you
need all
right
umur says what should I study to learn
Diplomat level
English okay you want to learn the kind
of English diplomats use what kind of
English do do diplomats use they use
Simple
English
so diplomats have two functions
H one function is to face the media and
the world and put out statements for the
media consumption for the consumption of
the media and the general
population these are statements made to
appease the media and appease the people
that's one function that diplomats serve
to put out official
statements the other function of
diplomats is to engage in negotiations
and diplomacy sometimes it's with
friendly countries in which there is a
warm and friendly environment sometimes
it is with hostile nations in which
there is outright bullying and threats
and arm
twisting so when you are facing the
media and you're making public
statements you use very vague diplomatic
language you generally use language that
can either have a very precise meaning
or you use language that can have lots
of different interpretations depending
on what you're trying to
achieve and so that is when you're
facing the media and facing the public
for public consumption the
other thing which you do behind closed
doors you have to be very precise in
that so you have to have a great amount
of command over whichever language
you're using in diplomacy in the past
the language of diplomacy was
French during the era of European
domination of the world but before that
it used to be in India and Asia Sanskrit
and whatever so whichever language you
use you need to have great command over
it you need to understand the nuances in
the context you need to know how to be
either very precise or to be very vague
so how do you st what should you study
to learn that level of English well you
need to
study you need to be you need to have a
very good command over English for that
which means you need to read a lot not
just your newspapers and and media
articles and all but even
literature even non-fiction you have to
read as much as you possibly can you
need to not just read but also write
writing is very important in diplomacy
you to put out diplomatic cables
communicates you need to have a very
very strong grasp on your written
communication it has to be very precise
very very very very uh the point so it's
not just about reading you need to be
able to read you need to be able to
write and you need to be able to speak
three different things and without
reading you can't achieve any of the
other two without reading a lot you
can't achieve a great command over
spoken or written language so the first
step is read a lot read a lot of high
quality literature high quality
Publications high quality non-fiction
read a lot don't read trash Pulp Fiction
level garbage Read Literature read uh
books on on History written by high
quality
historians read the history of the Cold
War read the history of the of the world
wars read the history of of
diplomacy all of that stuff so be
familiar with with the mil of diplomacy
The Diplomatic life and all
that read of authors you like them or
not people like kinger people like
brazinski and so many more so you have
to immerse yourself in this read a
tremendous amount write every single day
write a TH or 2,000 thousand words words
every day and keep on improving your
writing and learn how to communicate as
well you spoken
English so it's it's it's a big task but
certainly something that can be achieved
and if you do get into the field of
diplomacy ifs then you'll be actually
trained properly in that so yeah that's
how you do it that's how you do it read
a lot write a lot and and learn how to
speak okay
um okay Viv says please tell us about
solar storms and coronal mass ejection
in 2025 and what are its effects look I
can't look into the
future I don't know what's going to
happen 2025 I'm not an
astrologer and I'm not sure if we uh
have the scientific Kno how that allows
us to predict what will happen Visa the
Sun and uh it's Corona in the year 2025
I don't think we can but I can explain
what this is what is a solar storm it's
see look the sun is this big ball of
mainly hydrogen more than 99% hydrogen
some helium and some other elements a
whole bunch of other elements hopefully
not iron no iron
uh and it's it's undergoing nuclear
fusion at all times it's and and the
density of the sun is greater than that
of water
the sun is thicker the hydrogen soup is
thicker than water that's how dense it
is okay it is immense and it's a highly
magnetized star extremely powerful
magnetic
fields um and these magnetic lines of
force that twist and turn and they
combine with each each other and
sometimes they they snap off and that's
how you have these prominences solar
prominences which are you know uh these
these layers of plasma that l out of the
sun's surface and sometimes they get
thrown out the sun loses a certain
amount of plasma every second large
quantity actually which is called the
solar wind plasma is essentially ionized
hydrogen which is essentially protons
and electrons that flows out in the form
of solar wind and sometimes because of
sunspot activity and all that you have
extra a turbulent solar weather so you
have solar storms it is solar wind but
more turbulent and more energetic
essentially you can look at it like that
okay from a simplistic perspective that
is a solar ve solar storm coronal mass
ejection is when a large quantity of
solar material from the corona the
outermost layer of the sun is ejected
and that's something that happens from
time to time hopefully you don't want it
to come in your direction you want it to
miss the Earth so when you have a
coronal mass dection that comes towards
the Earth it's a tremendous amount of
solar plasma that's coming together it's
going to hit the earth now the Earth is
surrounded by a magnetic field of our
own which kind of shields us from the
solar wind and and and and cosmic rays
and all that uh but when a tremendous
quantity of of of solar plasma solar
wind comes and interact with the
magnetic field then you're going to
you're going to have
Electrical uh effects on in the Earth's
atmosphere you're going to have very
heightened uh
Aurora activity near the Earth's pools
the last time there was some such thing
we actually saw auroras from ladak in
Northern India and a strong enough
coronal mass ejection can actually end
up damaging or destroying electrical and
electronic infrastructure on the surface
of the
Earth um and it's going to happen
someday in the future maybe next year
maybe next decade Maybe Next Century
it's going to happen it's inevitable so
that is something that can destroy all
your communication satellites all your
low orbit High orbit geostationary orbit
satellites you may be left without any
Communications it may it can possibly
destroy all of your power grid so entire
nations can be left without power it can
cost hundreds of billions or trillions
of dollars worth of damage on the planet
it could take decades for the planet to
recover from that so that's what a solar
storm can do if it hits the Earth uh and
that is going to happen someday or the
other
okay harid Jen says what can Switzerland
do to protect its neutrality when the US
and EU start putting pressure the you
the Swiss have already buckled they are
no longer neutral uh I Think They
confiscated Russian bank accounts
something like that Switzerland is a
very small nation it it can't do much to
protect its sovereignty if the US puts
pressure the EU is simply a proxy of the
US not much the Swiss can do about it
not
much other says how can India establish
a strong Regional Presence
by by uh investing in power projection
capabilities in the regional domain
which means
submarines an augmented Navy large
quantities of fighter planes drones and
the ability to to do crossborder strikes
in a variety of ways all of that for
that you need money which means you have
to increase your economic output your
GDP annual GDP and you have to invest
all larger percentage of your GDP into
your defense budget that's how India can
establish a strong Regional pres and
obviously we have to engage with the
regional governments in the Indian
subcontinent we have many friendly
nations in the subcon Sri Lanka is an
example Nepal is an example Burma used
to be an example Bangladesh used to be
an example ban is an example and maybe
some others could be future friends so
engage with everybody who with whom we
can engage and of course the extended
neighborhood like Indonesia Thailand Etc
good friends we can we should engage
more with them that's what these are the
things India can do so invest in the
military power projection capabilities
invest in a stronger SP space
surveillance Network military satellites
all that and also engage with friendly
Nations and like-minded Nations
diplomatically all that you do that's
how establish a stronger Regional
presence
okay pratique says when do you think the
first human will step foot on Mars and
by when will we have a moon base look uh
the first human will most likely step
foot on Mars in the next four five years
if all goes to plan as per what Elon
Musk has
communicated so before 2030 most likely
the first human humans will land on Mars
most likely if it goes to plan Elon
musk's plan space X's plan second part
of the question when will we have a moon
bears I assume when you say V it means
India um the Americans are planning to
go back to the Moon human landing on the
moon in the next couple of years by 25
26 next couple of years so the Americans
will land on the Moon by the time the
Chinese are hoping to land humans on the
Moon by 2030 or thereabouts
uh India will need multiple chandrian
missions before we have the capability
to do that and India will have uh will
have a few launches of the gagan program
so we will have the first human space
flight in low earth orbit by 2526 India
by the 2030s India will have most likely
A small basic uh space station in orbit
around the
Earth and according to what ISRO has put
out by 2040 or something India will land
humans on the
moon um I was hoping we would do that by
2035 on chandran 10 but yeah that's the
that seems to be the plan the timeline
that isra has put out so yeah that seems
to be the timeline of human exploration
on Mars the US in the next on on the
moon the US by 25 or 26 China perhaps by
2030 India perhaps by 2040 Russia also
will have its plans Japan Also may be
allowed to do something by the Americans
let's see how it goes but that seems to
be the kind of timeline that we are
looking at and with that we come to the
end of today's session we are once again
cross 2 hours 12 minutes and uh yeah
with that I'm going to end this session
thank you so very much for all the
questions I hope we have taken a good
sample of various kinds of questions and
I'm going to take a whole bunch more
tomorrow so thank you so much for your
questions apologies to those of you
whose questions I could not take I know
there are thousands of them
can't take them all very sorry but we're
going to keep on doing this and I'm
going to take as many questions I as I
can in the days and weeks coming up so
thank you so much and I will see you I
hope to see you all in tomorrow's live
stream same time same channel 9 900 P.M
istd tomorrow until then take care thank
you very much for watching and keep
raising your standards bye